Willison, Malcolm; Papers apap055
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Promote and facilitate cooperation among employee-owned enterprises in the region and with similar efforts throughout the country. [See EOP brochure. Series 7, Box 1, Folder 2].
Social Activists and Public Advocates; Schenectady, New York; Rensselaer County, New York; Neighborhood and Community Associations; Military and Armed Conflict; Labor; Education; Conservation and the Environment; Albany, New York; Economic conversion; Economic development--Environmental aspects--United States; Environmental policy--New York (State); Peace--Study and teaching--United States; Bylaws; Correspondence; Minutes; Publications; Willison, Malcolm; Study Circle Consortium; Clergy and Laity Concerned (U.S.); Employee Ownership Project; Schenectady Peace and Justice Center; Neighborhood Action Coalition of Troy (Troy, N.Y.); Capital District Transportation Committee (Albany, N.Y.); Clean Air/Transportation Committee (Albany, N.Y.); Schenectady 2000 (Schenectady, N.Y.); Saratoga Peace Alliance, (Saratoga, N.Y.)
- Study Circles, 1975-1991; 1; 2 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1 consists of information tracing the study circle movement back to the 1970s. The series contains historical information about the Study Circle Consortium of New York State including meeting minutes, correspondence, pamphlets and membership information. Included are various published articles directly related to the study circle initiative both in Sweden and the US, along with files about various individual study circles including the circles on nuclear disarmament, parenting, child abuse, the environment, the Domestic Policy Association, quality circles, and others. There is also oversized material available in this series.
  - "Action Education: Using Study Circles to Build Student Leadership Teams", 1990 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 1)
  - Adelphi University, Community Education through Community Circles, 1982 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 2)
  - Adolescents and Teens, 1980-1982 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 3)
  - Aging and the Elderly, 1981-1985 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 4)
  - Adult Education, 1977-1988 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 5)
  - Adult Education, Sweden, 1980-1988 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 6)
  - Adult Education, Sweden, "Implementing Recurrent Education in Sweden", 1988 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 7)
  - Article, "The Art of Collaborative Learning", 1987 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 8)
  - Article, "Beyond the Myths: Families Helped by the AFDC Program", 1985 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 9)
  - Article, "Collaborative Learning: Recognizing It When We See It", 1988 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 10)
  - Article, "Dig Where You Stand", 1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 11)
  - Article, "Education by the People", 1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 12)
  - Article, "Informal Adult Learning", 1981 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 13)
  - Article, "Informal Adult Learning and Public Policy Issues: The Study Circle Approach", 1981 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 14)
  - Article, "Learning Communities for Curriculum and Staff Development", 1986 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 15)
  - Article, "The Learning Group: What It Is and Why It May Be Better", 1982 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 16)
  - Article, "The Scandinavian Study Circle: An Idea for the US?", 1982 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 17)
  - Article, "The Soaring Costs of Healthcare", Undated (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 18)
  - Article, "The Social and Economic Reform in Bulgaria: Economic Democracy and Problems of Change in Industrial Relations", 1989 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 19)
  - Article, "Students in Learning Groups: Active Learning through Conversation", 1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 20)
  - Article, "Study Circles: An Approach to Understanding Child Abuse and Neglect", Undated (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 21)
  - Article, "Study Circles: Learning in Small Groups", 1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 22)
  - Article, "Study Circles: Personal and Professional Fulfillment for Employees", 1982 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 23)
  - Article, "Teachers and Learning Groups: Dissolution of the Atlas Complex", 1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 24)
  - Article, "Training for Effective Collaborative Learning", 1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 25)
  - Article, "What Happens When Workers Manage Themselves", 1981 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 26)
  - Article, "Workplace Democracy in Bulgaria: From Subordination to Partnership in Industrial Relations", Undated (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 27)
  - The Arts, 1980-1986 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 28)
  - The Arts, 1980-1986 (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography on Study Circles, 1980-1982 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 29)
  - Building a Learning Society Conference, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 30)
  - Child Abuse and Neglect, 1982-1987 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 31)
  - Citizenship, 1981 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 32)
  - Chautauqua Lectures Circle Proposal, 1975-1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 33)
  - Community Development, 1979-1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 34)
  - Community Education, 1982 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 35)
  - Community Gardens, Troy, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 36)
  - Computer Networks, 1977-1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 37)
  - Continuing Education Association Conference, Keynote Address, 1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 38)
  - Cooperative Extension, Shared Housing, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 39)
  - Department of Social Services, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 40)
  - Domestic Policy Association, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 41)
  - Domestic Policy Association, "The Domestic Policy Association and Continuing Education: A Handbook", Undated (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 42)
  - Domestic Policy Association, "How to Enhance Citizen Participation in Public Life?", 1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 43)
  - Domestic Policy Association Kettering Review, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 44)
  - Domestic Policy Association, National Issues Forum, Issue Books, 1983-1985 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 45)
  - Domestic Policy Association, National Issues Forum, Newsletter, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 46)
  - Domestic Policy Association, National Issues Forum, Berks Community Television (BCTV), 1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 47)
  - Domestic Policy Association, National Issues Forum, Program Updates, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 48)
  - Domestic Policy Association, National Issues Forum, "Study Circles: A Handbook", Undated (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 49)
  - Domestic Policy Association, "Study Circles in the DPA: A Handbook", 1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 50)
  - Educators for Social Responsibility, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 51)
  - Excellence in Management Program, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 52)
  - Facilitators' Circle, 1983 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 53)
  - Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting (FAIR), 1987 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 54)
  - FHA/HERO in the Classroom, 1988 (Box 1 (1-Study Circles), Folder 55)
  - Higher Education Opportunity Program (HEOP), 1982 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 1)
  - New Sweden '88 Seminars: Swedish and American Approaches to Contemporary Issues, 1988 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 2)
  - A New World of Work, 1988 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 3)
  - New York State Legislature, 1979-1982 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 4)
  - Notes, 1980-1987 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Disarmament, Disarming Images Study Circle, 1985 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 6)
  - Participation and Schools, Undated (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 7)
  - People for the American Way, Undated (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 8)
  - Planners' Networks, 1981-1983 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 9)
  - Proposal for Bethlehem Town Board, New York, 1988 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 10)
  - Resource Allocation Plan (RAP), 1981 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 11)
  - Regional Planning, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 12)
  - Research and Central Development Work in Adult Education Associations and Folk High Schools, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 13)
  - The Study Circle: A Brief Introduction, 1979 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 14)
  - Sagamore Institute, 1975-1982 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 15)
  - Study Circle Consortium, By-Laws, 1984-1985 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 16)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 17)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Facilitator Training Program, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 18)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Guide to Classroom Study Circles, 1988 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 19)
  - Study Circle Consortium, History, 1981-1991 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 20)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Lifelong Learning Project, 1983 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 21)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Membership, 1983-1986 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 22)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Minutes, 1985-1988 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 23)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Newsletter, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 24)
  - Study Circle Consortium, New York State Education Department (Norman Kurland), 1983-1984 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 25)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Outreach, 1982-1984 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 26)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Parenting Circles, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 27)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Parenting Circles, 1982-1983 (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
  - Study Circle Consortium, "The Professional Role in Transition", 1980 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 28)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Quality Circles, 1981-1986 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 29)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Steering Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 30)
  - Study Circle Consortium, Subcommittee, 1983 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 31)
  - Study Circle Evaluations, 1981-1983 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 32)
  - Study Circle Resource Center, Public Talk Series, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 33)
  - Study Circles, Miscellaneous, 1982 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 34)
  - Study Guide, Community Development, Drafts, 1980 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 35)
  - Tips for Teaching Textiles and Clothing, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 36)
  - Troy Forum, 1982 (Box 2 (1-Study Circles), Folder 37)
- Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC), 1974-1988; 2; 1.4 cubic ft.
  Series 2 consists of CALC's minutes, membership information, and correspondence. However, the majority of files are specific to the issues that CALC deemed important, including the environment, politics, healthcare, peace and international relations. Various news clippings and initiatives on each of these topics shed light into CALC's overall goals and ideals. The series contains minutes and correspondence from the Schenectady Peace and Justice Center. There is also oversized material available in this series of presentation materials.
  - Central America, 1983-1988 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 1)
  - Central America, Berkshire Amistad, Undated (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 2)
  - Central America, Costa Rica, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 3)
  - Central America, El Salvador, 1984-1987 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 4)
  - Central America, Guatemala, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 5)
  - Central America, Nicaragua, 1984-1987 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 6)
  - Central America, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 7)
  - Central America, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 8)
  - Central America, Nuevo Instituto de Centro Amrica (NICA), 1986-1988 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 9)
  - Central America, NICA El Estiliano, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 10)
  - Central America, Report to the Community, 1986-1988 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 11)
  - Central America, Workshop on Central America, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 12)
  - Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC), Correspondence, Programming, etc., 1984-1986 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 13)
  - CALC, Membership, 1984-1986 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 14)
  - CALC, Minutes and Notes, 1983-1987 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 15)
  - CALC, Schenectady Peace and Justice Center, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 16)
  - CALC, Schenectady Peace and Justice Center, 1985-1987 (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
  - Economic Initiatives, 1979-1988 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 17)
  - Environmental Issues, 1979-1986 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 18)
  - Environmental Issues, The Adirondacks, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 19)
  - Environmental Issues, Energy, 1974-1982 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 20)
  - Environmental Issues, Generic Environmental Impact Statement for a Hazardous Waste Treatment Facility In New York State, Vols. I and II, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 21)
  - Environmental Issues, Hazardous and Toxic Waste, 1979-1983 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 22)
  - Environmental Issues, Industrial Hazardous Waste Generation in NYS, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 23)
  - Environmental Issues, Regulations for Implementing the Procedural Provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 24)
  - Environmental Issues, Study Guides, 1977-1982 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 25)
  - Environmental Issues, Syracuse, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 26)
  - Environmental Issues, Water, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 27)
  - General Electric, 1983-1985 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 28)
  - Habitat for Humanity, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 29)
  - Healthcare, 1974-1982 (Box 1 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 30)
  - Historic Preservation, 1978-1982 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 1)
  - Institute for Research on Poverty Publications, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 2)
  - Latin America, 1980-1987 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 3)
  - Mario Cuomo, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 4)
  - Native Americans, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Disarmament, 1982-1987 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 6)
  - Peace Initiatives, 1984-1987 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 7)
  - Peace Initiatives Kairos (Newsletter of Interfaith Center for Peace with Justice), 1987-1988 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 8)
  - Politics, 1980-1988 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 9)
  - Shad Alliance, Undated (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 10)
  - United States Military, 1984-1986 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 11)
  - United Way, 1978-1983 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 12)
  - Worker Democracy, 1978-1986 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 13)
  - World Federalist Association, 1986-1988 (Box 2 (2-Clergy and Laity Concerned (CALC)), Folder 14)
- Siena College, 1991-1992; 3; 1.4 cubic ft.
  Series 3 contains the materials used by Willison to teach Siena College courses in 1991 and 1992. The courses were Environmental Policy, Peace Studies, and Regional and Local Environmental Issues. Specific focus was put on the Hudson River, Love Canal, global warming, the Adirondacks, waste disposal, toxics, environmental racism and how environmental issues affect labor issues. The series includes several newsletters concerning environmental issues in the region. There is no one newsletter with a substantial consecutive run in the collection. There is also oversized material available in this series including newsletters and information about protecting James Bay in Quebec.
  - Audubon, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 1)
  - Capital District Greens, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 2)
  - Chernobyl, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 3)
  - Citizens' Environmental Coalition, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 6)
  - "Employment Impacts of Energy Development in New York State", 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 7)
  - Energy for Planet Earth, 1990 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 8)
  - Environment and Labor, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 9)
  - Environment and Labor Conference, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 10)
  - Environment and Labor Conference, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 11)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 12)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), The Adirondacks, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 13)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), The Adirondack Council, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 14)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), The Association for the Protection of the Adirondacks, Inc, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 15)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Clearwater, Inc, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 16)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Energy, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 17)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Global Warming, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 18)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Grades, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 19)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), The Hudson River, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 20)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Land Renewable, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 21)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 22)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Population, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 23)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Publication Information, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 24)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Student Evaluation Forms, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 25)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Toxics, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 26)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Toxics, The Military, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 27)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Waste Disposal, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 28)
  - Environmental Policy (AD-03), Water, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 29)
  - Environmental Racism, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 30)
  - Family Farm Alliance, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 31)
  - Greenpeace Initiatives, 1990-1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 32)
  - Interdisciplinary Studies (AD-04), Issues of Relativism and Truth: Environmental and Economic Survival, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 33)
  - Interdisciplinary Studies I: Regional and Local Environmental Issues, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 34)
  - Interdisciplinary Studies I, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 35)
  - Interdisciplinary Studies I: Regional and Local Environmental Issues, Love Canal, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 36)
  - Interdisciplinary Studies I: Regional and Local Environmental Issues, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 37)
  - Interdisciplinary Studies I: Regional and Local Environmental Issues, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 38)
  - International Environmentalism, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 39)
  - Introduction to Peace Studies (PC-01), 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 40)
  - James Bay, 1989-1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 41)
  - James Bay, 1989-1991 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
  - Legislation, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 42)
  - Magazines, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 43)
  - Magazines, 1991-1992 (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-1992 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
  - National Green Pages, 1993 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 45)
  - Newsletter Community Economics, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 46)
  - Newsletter Currents (Hudson River Environmental Society, Inc), 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 47)
  - Newsletter Don't Waste New York, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 48)
  - Newsletter The Guild Newsletter, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 49)
  - Newsletter NOFA-NY News (Natural Organic Farmers' Association of New York State), 1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 50)
  - Newsletter Waste Line (Citizens Against Radioactive Dumping), 1991-1992 (Box 1 (3-Siena College), Folder 51)
  - Newsletters, Miscellaneous Single Issues, 1990-1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, Miscellaneous Single Issues, 1990-1992 (Oversized 1, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, Miscellaneous Single Issues, 1990-1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 2)
  - New York State Environmental Congress, 1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 3)
  - New York under a Cloud: The Need to Prevent Toxic Chemical Accidents, 1991 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 4)
  - "The 1990s and Beyond" (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 5)
  - Pesticides, 1987-1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 6)
  - Pesticides, New York Coalition for Alternatives to Pesticides (NYCAP), 1991-1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 7)
  - Pesticides NYCAP News, 1990-1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 8)
  - Rio Earth Summit, 1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 9)
  - Schenectady FRIENDS of Human Services, 1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 10)
  - Social Movements and the Environment, Course, 1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 11)
  - Social Movements and the Environment, Course, 1992 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 12)
  - Solicitations, Undated (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 13)
  - Solicitations, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 8)
  - "Trading away the Environment", 1990 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 14)
  - "Why the Fight over Peace Studies", 1988 (Box 2 (3-Siena College), Folder 15)
- Economic Conversion, 1979-1994; 4; 3 cubic ft.
  This series contains the records of the Capital-Berkshire Area Economic Conversion Study Group and Task Force (CABEC). The collection contains information about the organization and its activities from 1986-1992. Series 4 also contains information on several other local groups that supported economic conversion. Many of the groups fell under the umbrella of the Social Justice Center. There are also several news clippings and reports that help shed light on the issues surrounding economic conversion.
  - Albany Peace and Energy Council (APEC), 1986-1989 (Box 1 (4-Economic Conversion), Folder 1)
  - Annual Survey of Manufacturers, 1981 (Box 1 (4-Economic Conversion), Folder 2)
  - Article, "The Best Defense is a Good Conversion", 1993 (Box 1 (4-Economic Conversion), Folder 3)
  - Article, "Can Economics Contribute to Peace?", 1988 (Box 1 (4-Economic Conversion), Folder 4)
  - Article, "Converting the Military through the Local State", 1988 (Box 1 (4-Economic Conversion), Folder 5)
  - Article, "Disarmament and the Economy: Catholic Social Thought and Economic Conversion", 1987 (Box 1 (4-Economic Conversion), Folder 6)